[
    {
        "question_no.": 1,
        "Question": "Which Roman general and statesman was assassinated by a group of senators, including Brutus?",
        "Option1": "Augustus",
        "Option2": "Julius Caesar",
        "Option3": "Mark Antony",
        "Option4": "Nero",
        "Answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 2,
        "Question": "Who was the first emperor of the Roman Empire?",
        "Option1": "Julius Caesar",
        "Option2": "Augustus",
        "Option3": "Caligula",
        "Option4": "Constantine the Great",
        "Answer": "Augustus"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 3,
        "Question": "Known for his military genius, which Macedonian king conquered most of the known world in his time?",
        "Option1": "Philip II",
        "Option2": "Darius III",
        "Option3": "Alexander the Great",
        "Option4": "Leonidas",
        "Answer": "Alexander the Great"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 4,
        "Question": "Who was the last pharaoh of ancient Egypt?",
        "Option1": "Nefertiti",
        "Option2": "Hatshepsut",
        "Option3": "Cleopatra VII",
        "Option4": "Tutankhamun",
        "Answer": "Cleopatra VII"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 5,
        "Question": "This Chinese emperor is credited with unifying China and building the Terracotta Army for his tomb.",
        "Option1": "Qin Shi Huang",
        "Option2": "Kublai Khan",
        "Option3": "Yongle Emperor",
        "Option4": "Emperor Wu of Han",
        "Answer": "Qin Shi Huang"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 6,
        "Question": "What Mongol leader founded the largest contiguous land empire in history?",
        "Option1": "Subutai",
        "Option2": "Kublai Khan",
        "Option3": "Genghis Khan",
        "Option4": "Timur",
        "Answer": "Genghis Khan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 7,
        "Question": "Which English king, known as the Lionheart, led the Third Crusade?",
        "Option1": "King John",
        "Option2": "Henry V",
        "Option3": "Richard I",
        "Option4": "Edward III",
        "Answer": "Richard I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 8,
        "Question": "Who was the peasant girl who led the French army to victory during the Hundred Years' War?",
        "Option1": "Marie Antoinette",
        "Option2": "Joan of Arc",
        "Option3": "Eleanor of Aquitaine",
        "Option4": "Catherine the Great",
        "Answer": "Joan of Arc"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 9,
        "Question": "This English queen reigned for 63 years and gave her name to an entire era of British history.",
        "Option1": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option2": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Elizabeth II",
        "Answer": "Queen Victoria"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 10,
        "Question": "Known for his 'I Have a Dream' speech, which American civil rights leader fought for racial equality?",
        "Option1": "Malcolm X",
        "Option2": "Rosa Parks",
        "Option3": "Martin Luther King Jr.",
        "Option4": "Booker T. Washington",
        "Answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 11,
        "Question": "Who was the first President of the United States?",
        "Option1": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Option2": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "John Adams",
        "Answer": "George Washington"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 12,
        "Question": "Which French military and political leader rose to prominence during the French Revolution and crowned himself Emperor?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Robespierre",
        "Option3": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option4": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 13,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option3": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 14,
        "Question": "Who was the first female Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?",
        "Option1": "Theresa May",
        "Option2": "Margaret Thatcher",
        "Option3": "Elizabeth Truss",
        "Option4": "Angela Merkel",
        "Answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 15,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Iron Chancellor,' which statesman unified Germany in the 19th century?",
        "Option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option4": "Ludwig III",
        "Answer": "Otto von Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 16,
        "Question": "Who was the Soviet dictator during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option3": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option4": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 17,
        "Question": "This English playwright and poet is widely regarded as the greatest writer in the English language.",
        "Option1": "Geoffrey Chaucer",
        "Option2": "William Wordsworth",
        "Option3": "William Shakespeare",
        "Option4": "Charles Dickens",
        "Answer": "William Shakespeare"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 18,
        "Question": "Which Renaissance artist painted the 'Mona Lisa' and 'The Last Supper'?",
        "Option1": "Michelangelo",
        "Option2": "Raphael",
        "Option3": "Leonardo da Vinci",
        "Option4": "Donatello",
        "Answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 19,
        "Question": "This physicist developed the theory of relativity and is one of the most famous scientists of all time.",
        "Option1": "Isaac Newton",
        "Option2": "Stephen Hawking",
        "Option3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Option4": "Galileo Galilei",
        "Answer": "Albert Einstein"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 20,
        "Question": "Which Polish-French physicist was a pioneer in radioactivity and the first person to win two Nobel Prizes?",
        "Option1": "Rosalind Franklin",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Lise Meitner",
        "Option4": "Dorothy Crowfoot Hodgkin",
        "Answer": "Marie Curie"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 21,
        "Question": "Known for his paintings 'The Starry Night' and 'Sunflowers,' who was this Dutch Post-Impressionist painter?",
        "Option1": "Claude Monet",
        "Option2": "Paul CÃ©zanne",
        "Option3": "Vincent van Gogh",
        "Option4": "Paul Gauguin",
        "Answer": "Vincent van Gogh"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 22,
        "Question": "Which Austrian composer was a child prodigy who composed over 600 works?",
        "Option1": "Ludwig van Beethoven",
        "Option2": "Johann Sebastian Bach",
        "Option3": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
        "Option4": "Franz Schubert",
        "Answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 23,
        "Question": "This Italian explorer is famous for his four voyages across the Atlantic Ocean.",
        "Option1": "Vasco da Gama",
        "Option2": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option3": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Option4": "Marco Polo",
        "Answer": "Christopher Columbus"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 24,
        "Question": "Known for his theory of natural selection, who was this English naturalist and biologist?",
        "Option1": "Gregor Mendel",
        "Option2": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option3": "Charles Darwin",
        "Option4": "Alfred Russel Wallace",
        "Answer": "Charles Darwin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 25,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 26,
        "Question": "Who was the first female prime minister of India?",
        "Option1": "Indira Gandhi",
        "Option2": "Sonia Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Pratibha Patil",
        "Option4": "Sarojini Naidu",
        "Answer": "Indira Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 27,
        "Question": "Which American inventor and businessman founded the Ford Motor Company?",
        "Option1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option2": "Henry Ford",
        "Option3": "Karl Benz",
        "Option4": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Answer": "Henry Ford"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 28,
        "Question": "This ancient Greek philosopher was a student of Plato and teacher of Alexander the Great.",
        "Option1": "Socrates",
        "Option2": "Aristotle",
        "Option3": "Pythagoras",
        "Option4": "Herodotus",
        "Answer": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 29,
        "Question": "Who was the founder of the religion of Islam?",
        "Option1": "Jesus",
        "Option2": "Abraham",
        "Option3": "Muhammad",
        "Option4": "Buddha",
        "Answer": "Muhammad"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 30,
        "Question": "This English scientist developed the theory of gravity and laws of motion.",
        "Option1": "Albert Einstein",
        "Option2": "Galileo Galilei",
        "Option3": "Isaac Newton",
        "Option4": "Stephen Hawking",
        "Answer": "Isaac Newton"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 31,
        "Question": "Which Russian political leader was the first head of the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option2": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option3": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
        "Option4": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Answer": "Vladimir Lenin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 32,
        "Question": "Known for his role in the American Revolution, this Founding Father was a scientist and inventor.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "Alexander Hamilton",
        "Option4": "Paul Revere",
        "Answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 33,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 34,
        "Question": "What French military leader was the Emperor of the French from 1852 to 1870?",
        "Option1": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option2": "Louis XIV",
        "Option3": "Napoleon III",
        "Option4": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Answer": "Napoleon III"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 35,
        "Question": "This German composer is one of the most influential figures in the history of Western music.",
        "Option1": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
        "Option2": "Johann Sebastian Bach",
        "Option3": "Ludwig van Beethoven",
        "Option4": "FrÃ©dÃ©ric Chopin",
        "Answer": "Johann Sebastian Bach"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 36,
        "Question": "Which American President delivered the 'Gettysburg Address' during the Civil War?",
        "Option1": "George Washington",
        "Option2": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Option3": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "Option4": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "Answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 37,
        "Question": "This Spanish conquistador led an expedition that caused the fall of the Aztec Empire.",
        "Option1": "Francisco Pizarro",
        "Option2": "HernÃ¡n CortÃ©s",
        "Option3": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option4": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Answer": "HernÃ¡n CortÃ©s"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 38,
        "Question": "Who was the first female ruler of Russia, known for her long and influential reign?",
        "Option1": "Tsarina Anastasia",
        "Option2": "Empress Catherine the Great",
        "Option3": "Empress Anna",
        "Option4": "Empress Elizabeth",
        "Answer": "Empress Catherine the Great"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 39,
        "Question": "Known as the 'Father of the Pakistani Nation,' who was this founder of Pakistan?",
        "Option1": "Allama Iqbal",
        "Option2": "Liaquat Ali Khan",
        "Option3": "Muhammad Ali Jinnah",
        "Option4": "Ayub Khan",
        "Answer": "Muhammad Ali Jinnah"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 40,
        "Question": "Which American President was a key figure in the Cold War and the Vietnam War?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 41,
        "Question": "What Mexican painter is famous for her self-portraits and works inspired by Mexican culture?",
        "Option1": "Frida Kahlo",
        "Option2": "Diego Rivera",
        "Option3": "Leonora Carrington",
        "Option4": "Remedios Varo",
        "Answer": "Frida Kahlo"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 42,
        "Question": "This revolutionary and political leader was the first Prime Minister of Israel.",
        "Option1": "Golda Meir",
        "Option2": "David Ben-Gurion",
        "Option3": "Yitzhak Rabin",
        "Option4": "Menachem Begin",
        "Answer": "David Ben-Gurion"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 43,
        "Question": "Which Spanish surrealist artist is known for his work 'The Persistence of Memory'?",
        "Option1": "Pablo Picasso",
        "Option2": "Salvador DalÃ­",
        "Option3": "Joan MirÃ³",
        "Option4": "Francisco Goya",
        "Answer": "Salvador DalÃ­"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 44,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Sun King,' which French king had the longest reign in European history?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Louis XVI",
        "Option3": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option4": "Henry IV",
        "Answer": "Louis XIV"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 45,
        "Question": "This English scientist and inventor is credited with creating the first practical light bulb.",
        "Option1": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Option2": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Option3": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option4": "James Watt",
        "Answer": "Thomas Edison"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 46,
        "Question": "Which Indian leader, known as 'Netaji,' was a key figure in the Indian independence movement?",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option3": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Subhas Chandra Bose"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 47,
        "Question": "Who was the first female president of a country in Latin America?",
        "Option1": "Isabel PerÃ³n",
        "Option2": "Michelle Bachelet",
        "Option3": "Dilma Rousseff",
        "Option4": "Cristina FernÃ¡ndez de Kirchner",
        "Answer": "Isabel PerÃ³n"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 48,
        "Question": "This Chinese Communist revolutionary was the founding father of the People's Republic of China.",
        "Option1": "Sun Yat-sen",
        "Option2": "Deng Xiaoping",
        "Option3": "Chiang Kai-shek",
        "Option4": "Mao Zedong",
        "Answer": "Mao Zedong"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 49,
        "Question": "Who was the Roman Emperor who made Christianity the state religion of the Roman Empire?",
        "Option1": "Nero",
        "Option2": "Diocletian",
        "Option3": "Constantine the Great",
        "Option4": "Augustus",
        "Answer": "Constantine the Great"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 50,
        "Question": "This Greek philosopher was a student of Socrates and wrote 'The Republic.'",
        "Option1": "Aristotle",
        "Option2": "Herodotus",
        "Option3": "Plato",
        "Option4": "Pythagoras",
        "Answer": "Plato"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 51,
        "Question": "Who was the American abolitionist who famously led the raid on Harpers Ferry?",
        "Option1": "Frederick Douglass",
        "Option2": "Harriet Tubman",
        "Option3": "John Brown",
        "Option4": "William Lloyd Garrison",
        "Answer": "John Brown"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 52,
        "Question": "This Hungarian composer is known for his piano music and for developing the symphonic poem.",
        "Option1": "Franz Liszt",
        "Option2": "BÃ©la BartÃ³k",
        "Option3": "Gustav Mahler",
        "Option4": "Franz Schubert",
        "Answer": "Franz Liszt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 53,
        "Question": "Who was the American statesman who served as the third President of the United States?",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Option4": "Alexander Hamilton",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 54,
        "Question": "This English monarch founded the Church of England after breaking away from the Roman Catholic Church.",
        "Option1": "Henry V",
        "Option2": "Henry VIII",
        "Option3": "Edward VI",
        "Option4": "James I",
        "Answer": "Henry VIII"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 55,
        "Question": "Which Russian Tsar was known for his reforms aimed at modernizing Russia along Western lines?",
        "Option1": "Peter the Great",
        "Option2": "Ivan the Terrible",
        "Option3": "Nicholas II",
        "Option4": "Catherine the Great",
        "Answer": "Peter the Great"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 56,
        "Question": "This Polish astronomer proposed a heliocentric model of the universe.",
        "Option1": "Johannes Kepler",
        "Option2": "Galileo Galilei",
        "Option3": "Tycho Brahe",
        "Option4": "Nicolaus Copernicus",
        "Answer": "Nicolaus Copernicus"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 57,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union during the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
        "Option1": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option2": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option3": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
        "Option4": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Answer": "Nikita Khrushchev"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 58,
        "Question": "This Scottish inventor and engineer is widely credited with inventing the telephone.",
        "Option1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option2": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Option3": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Option4": "James Watt",
        "Answer": "Alexander Graham Bell"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 59,
        "Question": "Which American President was a key figure in the Cold War and the Vietnam War?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 60,
        "Question": "This famous explorer was the first to circumnavigate the globe, though he died during the journey.",
        "Option1": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Option2": "Vasco da Gama",
        "Option3": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option4": "Marco Polo",
        "Answer": "Ferdinand Magellan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 61,
        "Question": "Which French general led the Free French Forces during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Philippe PÃ©tain",
        "Option2": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option3": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option4": "Jean-Luc MÃ©lenchon",
        "Answer": "Charles de Gaulle"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 62,
        "Question": "Known for his role in the American Civil War, who was the commander of the Confederate Army?",
        "Option1": "Ulysses S. Grant",
        "Option2": "Robert E. Lee",
        "Option3": "Stonewall Jackson",
        "Option4": "William Tecumseh Sherman",
        "Answer": "Robert E. Lee"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 63,
        "Question": "Who was the last Tsar of Russia, executed along with his family during the Russian Revolution?",
        "Option1": "Peter the Great",
        "Option2": "Alexander II",
        "Option3": "Nicholas II",
        "Option4": "Ivan the Terrible",
        "Answer": "Nicholas II"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 64,
        "Question": "This American President was a key figure in the American Revolution and helped draft the Declaration of Independence.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 65,
        "Question": "Which British Prime Minister led the UK during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option2": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "Tony Blair",
        "Answer": "Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 66,
        "Question": "Known for his 'Common Sense' pamphlet, which political activist influenced the American Revolution?",
        "Option1": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option2": "Thomas Paine",
        "Option3": "Samuel Adams",
        "Option4": "John Adams",
        "Answer": "Thomas Paine"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 67,
        "Question": "This Spanish painter and sculptor is one of the most famous artists of the 20th century, known for co-founding the Cubist movement.",
        "Option1": "Salvador DalÃ­",
        "Option2": "Pablo Picasso",
        "Option3": "Vincent van Gogh",
        "Option4": "Leonardo da Vinci",
        "Answer": "Pablo Picasso"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 68,
        "Question": "Who was the Egyptian president who signed the Camp David Accords with Israel?",
        "Option1": "Anwar Sadat",
        "Option2": "Gamal Abdel Nasser",
        "Option3": "Hosni Mubarak",
        "Option4": "Mohamed Morsi",
        "Answer": "Anwar Sadat"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 69,
        "Question": "This Chinese philosopher and statesman is the founder of Confucianism.",
        "Option1": "Laozi",
        "Option2": "Sun Tzu",
        "Option3": "Mencius",
        "Option4": "Confucius",
        "Answer": "Confucius"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 70,
        "Question": "Who was the American inventor who developed the first practical telephone?",
        "Option1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option2": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Option3": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Option4": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Answer": "Alexander Graham Bell"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 71,
        "Question": "This Greek philosopher was a student of Plato and teacher of Alexander the Great.",
        "Option1": "Socrates",
        "Option2": "Aristotle",
        "Option3": "Pythagoras",
        "Option4": "Herodotus",
        "Answer": "Aristotle"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 72,
        "Question": "Who was the founder of the religion of Islam?",
        "Option1": "Jesus",
        "Option2": "Abraham",
        "Option3": "Muhammad",
        "Option4": "Buddha",
        "Answer": "Muhammad"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 73,
        "Question": "This English scientist developed the theory of gravity and laws of motion.",
        "Option1": "Albert Einstein",
        "Option2": "Galileo Galilei",
        "Option3": "Isaac Newton",
        "Option4": "Stephen Hawking",
        "Answer": "Isaac Newton"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 74,
        "Question": "Which Russian political leader was the first head of the Soviet Union?",
        "Option1": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option2": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option3": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
        "Option4": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Answer": "Vladimir Lenin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 75,
        "Question": "Known for his role in the American Revolution, this Founding Father was a scientist and inventor.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "Alexander Hamilton",
        "Option4": "Paul Revere",
        "Answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 76,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 77,
        "Question": "What French military leader was the Emperor of the French from 1852 to 1870?",
        "Option1": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option2": "Louis XIV",
        "Option3": "Napoleon III",
        "Option4": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Answer": "Napoleon III"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 78,
        "Question": "This German composer is one of the most influential figures in the history of Western music.",
        "Option1": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
        "Option2": "Johann Sebastian Bach",
        "Option3": "Ludwig van Beethoven",
        "Option4": "FrÃ©dÃ©ric Chopin",
        "Answer": "Johann Sebastian Bach"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 79,
        "Question": "Which American President delivered the 'Gettysburg Address' during the Civil War?",
        "Option1": "George Washington",
        "Option2": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Option3": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "Option4": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "Answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 80,
        "Question": "This Spanish conquistador led an expedition that caused the fall of the Aztec Empire.",
        "Option1": "Francisco Pizarro",
        "Option2": "HernÃ¡n CortÃ©s",
        "Option3": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option4": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Answer": "HernÃ¡n CortÃ©s"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 81,
        "Question": "Who was the first female ruler of Russia, known for her long and influential reign?",
        "Option1": "Tsarina Anastasia",
        "Option2": "Empress Catherine the Great",
        "Option3": "Empress Anna",
        "Option4": "Empress Elizabeth",
        "Answer": "Empress Catherine the Great"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 82,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Sun King,' which French king had the longest reign in European history?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Louis XVI",
        "Option3": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option4": "Henry IV",
        "Answer": "Louis XIV"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 83,
        "Question": "This American inventor and businessman founded the Ford Motor Company?",
        "Option1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option2": "Henry Ford",
        "Option3": "Karl Benz",
        "Option4": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Answer": "Henry Ford"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 84,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 85,
        "Question": "Which Polish-French physicist was a pioneer in radioactivity and the first person to win two Nobel Prizes?",
        "Option1": "Rosalind Franklin",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Lise Meitner",
        "Option4": "Dorothy Crowfoot Hodgkin",
        "Answer": "Marie Curie"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 86,
        "Question": "Which of the following was the founder of the first Islamic state in the Arabian peninsula?",
        "Option1": "Abu Bakr",
        "Option2": "Umar",
        "Option3": "Muhammad",
        "Option4": "Ali",
        "Answer": "Muhammad"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 87,
        "Question": "Which Chinese leader is known for initiating the 'Great Leap Forward' and the 'Cultural Revolution'?",
        "Option1": "Deng Xiaoping",
        "Option2": "Mao Zedong",
        "Option3": "Chiang Kai-shek",
        "Option4": "Sun Yat-sen",
        "Answer": "Mao Zedong"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 88,
        "Question": "This German composer is widely regarded as the greatest figure in the history of Western music.",
        "Option1": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
        "Option2": "Johann Sebastian Bach",
        "Option3": "Ludwig van Beethoven",
        "Option4": "FrÃ©dÃ©ric Chopin",
        "Answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 89,
        "Question": "Known for his Theory of General Relativity, who was this physicist?",
        "Option1": "Isaac Newton",
        "Option2": "Stephen Hawking",
        "Option3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Option4": "Galileo Galilei",
        "Answer": "Albert Einstein"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 90,
        "Question": "Which American President was a key figure in the Cold War and the Vietnam War?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 91,
        "Question": "Which American President was a key figure in the Civil War?",
        "Option1": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "Option2": "Andrew Jackson",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 92,
        "Question": "Which British Prime Minister was in power during the Battle of Britain?",
        "Option1": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option2": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "Margaret Thatcher",
        "Answer": "Winston Churchill"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 93,
        "Question": "This famous explorer was the first to circumnavigate the globe, though he died during the journey.",
        "Option1": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Option2": "Vasco da Gama",
        "Option3": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option4": "Marco Polo",
        "Answer": "Ferdinand Magellan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 94,
        "Question": "Which French leader rose to prominence during the French Revolution and crowned himself Emperor?",
        "Option1": "Louis XVI",
        "Option2": "Robespierre",
        "Option3": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option4": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 95,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 96,
        "Question": "This English queen reigned for 63 years and gave her name to an entire era of British history.",
        "Option1": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option2": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Elizabeth II",
        "Answer": "Queen Victoria"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 97,
        "Question": "Known for his 'I Have a Dream' speech, which American civil rights leader fought for racial equality?",
        "Option1": "Malcolm X",
        "Option2": "Rosa Parks",
        "Option3": "Martin Luther King Jr.",
        "Option4": "Booker T. Washington",
        "Answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 98,
        "Question": "Who was the first female Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?",
        "Option1": "Theresa May",
        "Option2": "Margaret Thatcher",
        "Option3": "Elizabeth Truss",
        "Option4": "Angela Merkel",
        "Answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 99,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Iron Chancellor,' which statesman unified Germany in the 19th century?",
        "Option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option4": "Ludwig III",
        "Answer": "Otto von Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 100,
        "Question": "Who was the Soviet dictator during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option3": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option4": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 101,
        "Question": "Which American President was in office during the start of the Great Depression?",
        "Option1": "Calvin Coolidge",
        "Option2": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option3": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option4": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Answer": "Herbert Hoover"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 102,
        "Question": "This Spanish conquistador led an expedition that conquered the Inca Empire.",
        "Option1": "HernÃ¡n CortÃ©s",
        "Option2": "Francisco Pizarro",
        "Option3": "Juan Ponce de LeÃ³n",
        "Option4": "Vasco NÃºÃ±ez de Balboa",
        "Answer": "Francisco Pizarro"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 103,
        "Question": "Who was the first female US Secretary of State?",
        "Option1": "Madeleine Albright",
        "Option2": "Condoleezza Rice",
        "Option3": "Hillary Clinton",
        "Option4": "Janet Yellen",
        "Answer": "Madeleine Albright"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 104,
        "Question": "This American President was known for his 'New Deal' program to combat the Great Depression.",
        "Option1": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option4": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 105,
        "Question": "Which Roman emperor's reign marked the beginning of the Pax Romana?",
        "Option1": "Julius Caesar",
        "Option2": "Augustus",
        "Option3": "Nero",
        "Option4": "Constantine the Great",
        "Answer": "Augustus"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 106,
        "Question": "This physicist is known for his work on quantum mechanics and his famous equation, E = mcÂ².",
        "Option1": "Isaac Newton",
        "Option2": "Niels Bohr",
        "Option3": "Albert Einstein",
        "Option4": "Stephen Hawking",
        "Answer": "Albert Einstein"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 107,
        "Question": "Who was the last ruling monarch of Russia?",
        "Option1": "Peter the Great",
        "Option2": "Catherine the Great",
        "Option3": "Nicholas II",
        "Option4": "Alexander III",
        "Answer": "Nicholas II"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 108,
        "Question": "This American entrepreneur co-founded Apple Inc. and was a pioneer of the personal computer revolution.",
        "Option1": "Bill Gates",
        "Option2": "Steve Wozniak",
        "Option3": "Steve Jobs",
        "Option4": "Jeff Bezos",
        "Answer": "Steve Jobs"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 109,
        "Question": "Which famous explorer was the first European to sail to India?",
        "Option1": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Option2": "Vasco da Gama",
        "Option3": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option4": "Marco Polo",
        "Answer": "Vasco da Gama"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 110,
        "Question": "This British scientist discovered penicillin, the world's first antibiotic.",
        "Option1": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Option4": "Joseph Lister",
        "Answer": "Alexander Fleming"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 111,
        "Question": "Who was the American abolitionist who escaped slavery and became a powerful orator and writer?",
        "Option1": "Harriet Tubman",
        "Option2": "Sojourner Truth",
        "Option3": "Frederick Douglass",
        "Option4": "William Lloyd Garrison",
        "Answer": "Frederick Douglass"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 112,
        "Question": "This American President was the first to resign from office.",
        "Option1": "Bill Clinton",
        "Option2": "Jimmy Carter",
        "Option3": "Richard Nixon",
        "Option4": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Answer": "Richard Nixon"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 113,
        "Question": "Known for his role in the American Revolution, this general led the Continental Army.",
        "Option1": "Paul Revere",
        "Option2": "George Washington",
        "Option3": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option4": "John Adams",
        "Answer": "George Washington"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 114,
        "Question": "This German-born philosopher is considered the father of modern communism.",
        "Option1": "Friedrich Engels",
        "Option2": "Karl Marx",
        "Option3": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option4": "Mao Zedong",
        "Answer": "Karl Marx"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 115,
        "Question": "Who was the Italian Fascist dictator who allied with Adolf Hitler during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Francisco Franco",
        "Option2": "Benito Mussolini",
        "Option3": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option4": "Emperor Hirohito",
        "Answer": "Benito Mussolini"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 116,
        "Question": "Which famous figure from ancient Greece was known for being a philosopher who taught through questioning?",
        "Option1": "Plato",
        "Option2": "Aristotle",
        "Option3": "Socrates",
        "Option4": "Pericles",
        "Answer": "Socrates"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 117,
        "Question": "This Roman emperor divided the empire into two halves to improve administration.",
        "Option1": "Augustus",
        "Option2": "Nero",
        "Option3": "Diocletian",
        "Option4": "Constantine the Great",
        "Answer": "Diocletian"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 118,
        "Question": "Who was the first female US Supreme Court Justice?",
        "Option1": "Sonia Sotomayor",
        "Option2": "Ruth Bader Ginsburg",
        "Option3": "Elena Kagan",
        "Option4": "Sandra Day O'Connor",
        "Answer": "Sandra Day O'Connor"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 119,
        "Question": "This artist and sculptor is famous for his work on the Sistine Chapel ceiling.",
        "Option1": "Leonardo da Vinci",
        "Option2": "Raphael",
        "Option3": "Michelangelo",
        "Option4": "Donatello",
        "Answer": "Michelangelo"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 120,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union when the Berlin Wall fell?",
        "Option1": "Leonid Brezhnev",
        "Option2": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option3": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
        "Option4": "Yuri Andropov",
        "Answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 121,
        "Question": "This Queen of France was executed during the French Revolution.",
        "Option1": "Eleanor of Aquitaine",
        "Option2": "Catherine de' Medici",
        "Option3": "Marie Antoinette",
        "Option4": "Isabella I of Castile",
        "Answer": "Marie Antoinette"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 122,
        "Question": "Who was the American President who served two non-consecutive terms?",
        "Option1": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "Option2": "Grover Cleveland",
        "Option3": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "Option4": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "Answer": "Grover Cleveland"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 123,
        "Question": "This famous figure was a nurse during the Crimean War and is considered the founder of modern nursing.",
        "Option1": "Clara Barton",
        "Option2": "Florence Nightingale",
        "Option3": "Mother Teresa",
        "Option4": "Dorothea Dix",
        "Answer": "Florence Nightingale"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 124,
        "Question": "Which American President was a key figure in the Civil Rights Movement and signed the Civil Rights Act of 1964?",
        "Option1": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option2": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option3": "Richard Nixon",
        "Option4": "Jimmy Carter",
        "Answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 125,
        "Question": "This Portuguese explorer was the first European to reach India by sea, opening a new trade route.",
        "Option1": "Christopher Columbus",
        "Option2": "Ferdinand Magellan",
        "Option3": "Vasco da Gama",
        "Option4": "Bartolomeu Dias",
        "Answer": "Vasco da Gama"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 126,
        "Question": "Who was the leader of the Soviet Union who initiated the policies of 'glasnost' and 'perestroika'?",
        "Option1": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Option2": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option3": "Mikhail Gorbachev",
        "Option4": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 127,
        "Question": "This American President was a former actor and was in office when the Berlin Wall fell.",
        "Option1": "Jimmy Carter",
        "Option2": "Ronald Reagan",
        "Option3": "George H.W. Bush",
        "Option4": "Bill Clinton",
        "Answer": "Ronald Reagan"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 128,
        "Question": "Which British Prime Minister was known for his policy of appeasement towards Nazi Germany?",
        "Option1": "Winston Churchill",
        "Option2": "Neville Chamberlain",
        "Option3": "Clement Attlee",
        "Option4": "David Lloyd George",
        "Answer": "Neville Chamberlain"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 129,
        "Question": "This American inventor and engineer founded the first company to produce commercial light bulbs.",
        "Option1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option2": "Henry Ford",
        "Option3": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Option4": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Answer": "Thomas Edison"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 130,
        "Question": "Who was the famous German composer of the Classical and Romantic eras, known for his 'Symphony No. 5'?",
        "Option1": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
        "Option2": "Johann Sebastian Bach",
        "Option3": "Ludwig van Beethoven",
        "Option4": "FrÃ©dÃ©ric Chopin",
        "Answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 131,
        "Question": "Which American President was known for his 'Square Deal' domestic policy and his 'Big Stick' diplomacy?",
        "Option1": "Woodrow Wilson",
        "Option2": "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option4": "Abraham Lincoln",
        "Answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 132,
        "Question": "This famous figure was a nun and missionary known for her work with the poor in India.",
        "Option1": "Florence Nightingale",
        "Option2": "Mother Teresa",
        "Option3": "Clara Barton",
        "Option4": "Dorothea Dix",
        "Answer": "Mother Teresa"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 133,
        "Question": "Which American President was in office during the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 134,
        "Question": "Known for his role in the American Revolution, who was the main author of the Declaration of Independence?",
        "Option1": "George Washington",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Option4": "John Adams",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 135,
        "Question": "This famous figure was a leader of the women's suffrage movement in the United States.",
        "Option1": "Rosa Parks",
        "Option2": "Susan B. Anthony",
        "Option3": "Eleanor Roosevelt",
        "Option4": "Harriet Tubman",
        "Answer": "Susan B. Anthony"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 136,
        "Question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
        "Option1": "John A. Macdonald",
        "Option2": "Wilfrid Laurier",
        "Option3": "Pierre Trudeau",
        "Option4": "Lester B. Pearson",
        "Answer": "John A. Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 137,
        "Question": "This English scientist and physician developed the first vaccine, for smallpox.",
        "Option1": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option2": "Robert Koch",
        "Option3": "Edward Jenner",
        "Option4": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 138,
        "Question": "Which ancient Greek general and statesman was known for his leadership during the Peloponnesian War?",
        "Option1": "Alexander the Great",
        "Option2": "Leonidas",
        "Option3": "Pericles",
        "Option4": "Themistocles",
        "Answer": "Pericles"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 139,
        "Question": "Who was the last Empress of China?",
        "Option1": "Empress Wu Zetian",
        "Option2": "Empress Dowager Cixi",
        "Option3": "Empress Xiaoqinxian",
        "Option4": "Empress Wanrong",
        "Answer": "Empress Dowager Cixi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 140,
        "Question": "This American President was a key figure in the American Revolution and helped draft the Declaration of Independence.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 141,
        "Question": "Who was the famous French military leader and Emperor of the French?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option3": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option4": "Louis XVI",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 142,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 143,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 144,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 145,
        "Question": "Which Polish-French physicist was a pioneer in radioactivity and the first person to win two Nobel Prizes?",
        "Option1": "Rosalind Franklin",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Lise Meitner",
        "Option4": "Dorothy Crowfoot Hodgkin",
        "Answer": "Marie Curie"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 146,
        "Question": "Which American President was known for his 'New Deal' program to combat the Great Depression?",
        "Option1": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option4": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 147,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Iron Chancellor,' which statesman unified Germany in the 19th century?",
        "Option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option4": "Ludwig III",
        "Answer": "Otto von Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 148,
        "Question": "Who was the Soviet dictator during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option3": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option4": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 149,
        "Question": "This famous figure was a leader of the women's suffrage movement in the United States.",
        "Option1": "Rosa Parks",
        "Option2": "Susan B. Anthony",
        "Option3": "Eleanor Roosevelt",
        "Option4": "Harriet Tubman",
        "Answer": "Susan B. Anthony"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 150,
        "Question": "Which American President was in office during the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 151,
        "Question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
        "Option1": "John A. Macdonald",
        "Option2": "Wilfrid Laurier",
        "Option3": "Pierre Trudeau",
        "Option4": "Lester B. Pearson",
        "Answer": "John A. Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 152,
        "Question": "This English scientist and physician developed the first vaccine, for smallpox.",
        "Option1": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option2": "Robert Koch",
        "Option3": "Edward Jenner",
        "Option4": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 153,
        "Question": "Which ancient Greek general and statesman was known for his leadership during the Peloponnesian War?",
        "Option1": "Alexander the Great",
        "Option2": "Leonidas",
        "Option3": "Pericles",
        "Option4": "Themistocles",
        "Answer": "Pericles"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 154,
        "Question": "Who was the last Empress of China?",
        "Option1": "Empress Wu Zetian",
        "Option2": "Empress Dowager Cixi",
        "Option3": "Empress Xiaoqinxian",
        "Option4": "Empress Wanrong",
        "Answer": "Empress Dowager Cixi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 155,
        "Question": "This American President was a key figure in the American Revolution and helped draft the Declaration of Independence.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 156,
        "Question": "Who was the famous French military leader and Emperor of the French?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option3": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option4": "Louis XVI",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 157,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 158,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 159,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 160,
        "Question": "Which Polish-French physicist was a pioneer in radioactivity and the first person to win two Nobel Prizes?",
        "Option1": "Rosalind Franklin",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Lise Meitner",
        "Option4": "Dorothy Crowfoot Hodgkin",
        "Answer": "Marie Curie"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 161,
        "Question": "Which American President was known for his 'New Deal' program to combat the Great Depression?",
        "Option1": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option4": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 162,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Iron Chancellor,' which statesman unified Germany in the 19th century?",
        "Option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option4": "Ludwig III",
        "Answer": "Otto von Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 163,
        "Question": "Who was the Soviet dictator during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option3": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option4": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 164,
        "Question": "Which American President was in office during the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 165,
        "Question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
        "Option1": "John A. Macdonald",
        "Option2": "Wilfrid Laurier",
        "Option3": "Pierre Trudeau",
        "Option4": "Lester B. Pearson",
        "Answer": "John A. Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 166,
        "Question": "This English scientist and physician developed the first vaccine, for smallpox.",
        "Option1": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option2": "Robert Koch",
        "Option3": "Edward Jenner",
        "Option4": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 167,
        "Question": "Which ancient Greek general and statesman was known for his leadership during the Peloponnesian War?",
        "Option1": "Alexander the Great",
        "Option2": "Leonidas",
        "Option3": "Pericles",
        "Option4": "Themistocles",
        "Answer": "Pericles"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 168,
        "Question": "Who was the last Empress of China?",
        "Option1": "Empress Wu Zetian",
        "Option2": "Empress Dowager Cixi",
        "Option3": "Empress Xiaoqinxian",
        "Option4": "Empress Wanrong",
        "Answer": "Empress Dowager Cixi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 169,
        "Question": "This American President was a key figure in the American Revolution and helped draft the Declaration of Independence.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 170,
        "Question": "Who was the famous French military leader and Emperor of the French?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option3": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option4": "Louis XVI",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 171,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 172,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 173,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 174,
        "Question": "Which Polish-French physicist was a pioneer in radioactivity and the first person to win two Nobel Prizes?",
        "Option1": "Rosalind Franklin",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Lise Meitner",
        "Option4": "Dorothy Crowfoot Hodgkin",
        "Answer": "Marie Curie"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 175,
        "Question": "Which American President was known for his 'New Deal' program to combat the Great Depression?",
        "Option1": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option4": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 176,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Iron Chancellor,' which statesman unified Germany in the 19th century?",
        "Option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option4": "Ludwig III",
        "Answer": "Otto von Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 177,
        "Question": "Who was the Soviet dictator during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option3": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option4": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 178,
        "Question": "Which American President was in office during the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 179,
        "Question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
        "Option1": "John A. Macdonald",
        "Option2": "Wilfrid Laurier",
        "Option3": "Pierre Trudeau",
        "Option4": "Lester B. Pearson",
        "Answer": "John A. Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 180,
        "Question": "This English scientist and physician developed the first vaccine, for smallpox.",
        "Option1": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option2": "Robert Koch",
        "Option3": "Edward Jenner",
        "Option4": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 181,
        "Question": "Which ancient Greek general and statesman was known for his leadership during the Peloponnesian War?",
        "Option1": "Alexander the Great",
        "Option2": "Leonidas",
        "Option3": "Pericles",
        "Option4": "Themistocles",
        "Answer": "Pericles"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 182,
        "Question": "Who was the last Empress of China?",
        "Option1": "Empress Wu Zetian",
        "Option2": "Empress Dowager Cixi",
        "Option3": "Empress Xiaoqinxian",
        "Option4": "Empress Wanrong",
        "Answer": "Empress Dowager Cixi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 183,
        "Question": "This American President was a key figure in the American Revolution and helped draft the Declaration of Independence.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 184,
        "Question": "Who was the famous French military leader and Emperor of the French?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option3": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option4": "Louis XVI",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 185,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 186,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 187,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 188,
        "Question": "Which Polish-French physicist was a pioneer in radioactivity and the first person to win two Nobel Prizes?",
        "Option1": "Rosalind Franklin",
        "Option2": "Marie Curie",
        "Option3": "Lise Meitner",
        "Option4": "Dorothy Crowfoot Hodgkin",
        "Answer": "Marie Curie"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 189,
        "Question": "Which American President was known for his 'New Deal' program to combat the Great Depression?",
        "Option1": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option4": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 190,
        "Question": "Known as 'The Iron Chancellor,' which statesman unified Germany in the 19th century?",
        "Option1": "Kaiser Wilhelm II",
        "Option2": "Otto von Bismarck",
        "Option3": "Adolf Hitler",
        "Option4": "Ludwig III",
        "Answer": "Otto von Bismarck"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 191,
        "Question": "Who was the Soviet dictator during World War II?",
        "Option1": "Vladimir Lenin",
        "Option2": "Leon Trotsky",
        "Option3": "Nikita Khrushchev",
        "Option4": "Joseph Stalin",
        "Answer": "Joseph Stalin"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 192,
        "Question": "Who was the first female US Secretary of State?",
        "Option1": "Madeleine Albright",
        "Option2": "Condoleezza Rice",
        "Option3": "Hillary Clinton",
        "Option4": "Janet Yellen",
        "Answer": "Madeleine Albright"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 193,
        "Question": "This American President was known for his 'New Deal' program to combat the Great Depression.",
        "Option1": "Herbert Hoover",
        "Option2": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
        "Option3": "Harry S. Truman",
        "Option4": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 194,
        "Question": "Known for his 'I Have a Dream' speech, which American civil rights leader fought for racial equality?",
        "Option1": "Malcolm X",
        "Option2": "Rosa Parks",
        "Option3": "Martin Luther King Jr.",
        "Option4": "Booker T. Washington",
        "Answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 195,
        "Question": "Who was the American inventor who developed the first practical telephone?",
        "Option1": "Thomas Edison",
        "Option2": "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Option3": "Nikola Tesla",
        "Option4": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Answer": "Alexander Graham Bell"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 196,
        "Question": "This American President was in office during the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
        "Option1": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
        "Option2": "John F. Kennedy",
        "Option3": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
        "Option4": "Richard Nixon",
        "Answer": "John F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 197,
        "Question": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
        "Option1": "John A. Macdonald",
        "Option2": "Wilfrid Laurier",
        "Option3": "Pierre Trudeau",
        "Option4": "Lester B. Pearson",
        "Answer": "John A. Macdonald"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 198,
        "Question": "This English scientist and physician developed the first vaccine, for smallpox.",
        "Option1": "Louis Pasteur",
        "Option2": "Robert Koch",
        "Option3": "Edward Jenner",
        "Option4": "Alexander Fleming",
        "Answer": "Edward Jenner"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 199,
        "Question": "Which ancient Greek general and statesman was known for his leadership during the Peloponnesian War?",
        "Option1": "Alexander the Great",
        "Option2": "Leonidas",
        "Option3": "Pericles",
        "Option4": "Themistocles",
        "Answer": "Pericles"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 200,
        "Question": "Who was the last Empress of China?",
        "Option1": "Empress Wu Zetian",
        "Option2": "Empress Dowager Cixi",
        "Option3": "Empress Xiaoqinxian",
        "Option4": "Empress Wanrong",
        "Answer": "Empress Dowager Cixi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 201,
        "Question": "This American President was a key figure in the American Revolution and helped draft the Declaration of Independence.",
        "Option1": "John Adams",
        "Option2": "Benjamin Franklin",
        "Option3": "George Washington",
        "Option4": "Thomas Jefferson",
        "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 202,
        "Question": "Who was the famous French military leader and Emperor of the French?",
        "Option1": "Louis XIV",
        "Option2": "Napoleon Bonaparte",
        "Option3": "Charles de Gaulle",
        "Option4": "Louis XVI",
        "Answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 203,
        "Question": "This Indian activist led a nonviolent resistance movement to gain independence from British rule.",
        "Option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        "Option2": "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Option3": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        "Option4": "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        "Answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 204,
        "Question": "Which Queen of England was known for her long reign and was the last of the Tudor monarchs?",
        "Option1": "Queen Mary I",
        "Option2": "Queen Elizabeth I",
        "Option3": "Queen Victoria",
        "Option4": "Queen Anne",
        "Answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
    },
    {
        "question_no.": 205,
        "Question": "This former South African president was an anti-apartheid revolutionary who spent 27 years in prison.",
        "Option1": "F. W. de Klerk",
        "Option2": "Nelson Mandela",
        "Option3": "Desmond Tutu",
        "Option4": "Thabo Mbeki",
        "Answer": "Nelson Mandela"
    }
]